Guide to the Davies/Scroggie Collection of White Pass and Yukon Documents and Ephemera
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Davies/Scroggie Collection of White Pass and Yukon Documents and Ephemera
1899-1947
WA MSS S-2627
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6
(6 boxes)
The Davies/Scroggie Collection of White Pass and Yukon Documents and Ephemera provides evidence of commerce and transportation in the Yukon Territory and Alaska dating between 1899 and 1947. The Collection largely consists of time rolls and distribution of labor books documenting the firm White Pass and Yukon Route. Other material in the collection includes certificates, customs documents, bills, correspondence, and legal documents, which represent commerce, transportation, and the Klondike gold rush (which began in 1897). The Collection is useful for understanding labor history, daily life during the gold rush, and the complexities of railway construction in the Yukon Territory and Alaska.
Davies, Grant, 1947-
Davies, Carole-Ann Scroggie, 1949-
White Pass & Yukon Route (Firm)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Grant Davies and Carole-Ann Scroggie Davies, 1993-1994.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Davies/Scroggie Collection of White Pass and Yukon Documents and Ephemera provides evidence of commerce and transportation in the Yukon Territory and Alaska dating between 1899 and 1947. The Collection largely consists of time rolls and distribution of labor books documenting the firm White Pass and Yukon Route. Other material in the collection includes certificates, customs documents, bills, correspondence, and legal documents, which represent commerce, transportation, and the Klondike gold rush (which began in 1897). The Collection is useful for understanding labor history, daily life during the gold rush, and the complexities of railway construction in the Yukon Territory and Alaska.
Arrangement
The Davies/Scroggie Collection of White Pass and Yukon Documents and Ephemera is organized into two series: Commercial Documents and Ephemera and Transportation Documents and Ephemera.
Frontier and pioneer life -- Alaska; Frontier and pioneer life -- Northwest, Canadian; Gold mines and mining -- Yukon -- Klondike River Valley; Narrow gauge railroads -- Alaska; Narrow gauge railroads -- British Columbia; Narrow gauge railroads -- Yukon; Railroads -- Alaska -- Design and construction; Railroads -- Alaska -- Employees; Railroads -- Yukon -- Design and construction; Railroads -- Yukon -- Employees; Klondike River Valley (Yukon) -- Gold discoveries; Yukon Territory -- Gold discoveries; Payrolls; British Yukon Navigation Co; White Pass & Yukon Route (Firm); White Pass & Yukon Route (Firm) -- Accounting
- Commercial Documents and Ephemera, 1899-1946; Series I; 1; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains various documents and ephemera, dating from 1899 to 1946, pertaining to commerce in Alaska and the Yukon Territory. The series is comprised of certificates, customs documents, bills, and receipts, which provide insight into daily life in the gold rush period (particularly in Skagway). The export and royalty certificates, in particular, chronicle the gold trade and its participants.
  - Office of the Comptroller (Yukon Territory). Royalty certificates certifying payment of gold royalties, issued primarily at Dawson City but with some issued at Forty Mile and Whitehorse, 1901-1905 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Comptroller (Yukon Territory). Free certificates for the export of gold, all issued at Dawson City to banks, a variety of companies, and private citizens, 1905; 3 (Box 1)
  - Billheads, receipts, and commercial correspondence, 1899-1946 (Box 1)
    Largely from Skagway but also from Atlin, Dawson, Juneau, Ketchikan, Log Cabin, Valdez, and Whitehorse
  - Canada Customs documents, 1899 and 1906 (Box 1)
    Includes bills of sight
  - Pacific Contract Company documents and manuscripts, 1899-1901 (Box 1)
  - Water notice, 1899 (Box 1)
- Transportation Documents and Ephemera, 1899-1947; Series II; 5; (5 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The series is organized into two subseries: Various Companies and White Pass and Yukon Route (Firm).
  The series contains documents and ephemera, dating between 1899 and 1947, which record the development and operation of various companies in Alaska and the Yukon Territory. The materials explain how life and business could flourish despite travel and communications difficulties caused by the rugged terrain, the scattered settlements, and the severe weather. A substantial amount of material pertains to the various rail and river enterprises owned by the firm White Pass and Yukon Route and reveals how the company perceived its role in the territories and how it viewed its employees. The time rolls and distribution of labor books trace details such as the number of hours worked by employees, rate of hourly wages, and occupations, and thus constitute an important resource for labor history.
  - Various Companies
    - American Yukon Navigation Company. Documents, 1905-1924 (Box 1)
      Includes receipts and accounts of fuel consumption
    - The British Yukon Navigation Company, Limited. Documents including correspondence, internal financial documents (such as mortgage substitution account and reports on fuel consumption), vouchers, and trip passes, 1901-1947; 3 (Box 1)
    - British Yukon Railway Company. Legal documents including bill of sale, certificate of title, and resolution, 1905-1908 (Box 1)
  - White Pass and Yukon Route (Firm)
    - Correspondence, 1899-1947; 13 (Box 1)
      Includes correspondence from President, Vice-President, cashier, general manager, fuel agent, land and tax agent, purchasing agent, solicitor and general agent, superintendent (river division and rail division), traffic manager, and accounting department.
    - Auditor's bills, 1901-1926 (Box 1)
    - Baggage tags, undated (Box 1)
    - Tariffs and timetables, 1901-1947 (Box 1)
    - Tickets and passes, 1911 and 1946-1951; 3 (Box 1)
    - Wage cheques, 1901 (Box 1)
    - Time rolls and distribution of labor books, 1899 February - 1900 January; 15 (Box 2)
    - Time rolls and distribution of labor books, 1900 January - December and 1907-1909; 15 (Box 3)
    - Time books, 1900 March - July; 14 (Box 4)
    - Time books, 1900 August - October; 15 (Box 5)
    - Time books, 1900 November - December; 10 (Box 6)